<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Karachay-Cherkessia &#8211; Aslan Gotov</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/karachay-cherkessia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Musician, Composer, Arranger</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:31:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Karachay-Cherkessia &#8211; Aslan Gotov</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Murad Kazhlaev</title>
		<link>/2019/06/murad-kazhlaev/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 03:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Connections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karachay-Cherkessia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The name of composer, conductor, pedagogue, People&#8217;s Artist of USSR, and Professor Murad Kazhlaev is widely known to fans and admirers of music. The representative...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The name of composer, conductor, pedagogue, People&#8217;s Artist of USSR, and Professor Murad Kazhlaev is widely known to fans and admirers of music. The representative of one of the peoples of the Caucasus &#8211; Murad Kazhlaev was among the founders of the professional music of Dagestan. His creative work is inextricably linked with the life and music of his beautiful homeland, a country with an interesting history and a rich distinctive folklore.<br />
Murad Kazhlaev was born in 1931 in Baku in the physician family. Musical ability appeared to him early. Composition education he received at the Azerbaijan State Conservatory in the class of Professor BI Zeydman. In 1954, still a student at the conservatory, Kazhlaev was accepted as a member of the Union of Soviet Composers.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kazhl.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kazhl.jpg" alt="" width="492" height="114" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-517" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kazhl.jpg 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kazhl-300x70.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></a></p>
<p>     Murad Kazhlaev is an active composer, writer and public figure, the work which deserves to be very popular in Russia and abroad. His work has been international prizes and performed in Austria, Germany, England, United States, Japan, Czechoslovakia, Turkey, Egypt, Bulgaria, Italy, Poland and CIS countries. Capable gifted pianist and conductor, Murad Kazhlaev spent nearly 20 years in the Yuri Silantyev Academic Grand Concert Orchestra as the artistic director and principal conductor, combining this work with teaching in the Rostov State Conservatory named after Sergei Rakhmaninov.</p>
<p>       M. Kazhlaev has many concerts, promoting classical, contemporary, symphonic, pop-jazz music of Russia and the best examples of the works of composers abroad.</p>
<p>       The list of works of M. Kazhlaev is more than 300 items, among which the First Daghestan Symphony (1955), the First Dagestan national ballet &#8220;Gorianka&#8221; (1968), revue Million Bridal &#8220;(1971), symphonic dance-pictures (1974), symphonic pictures &#8220;Farhad and Shirin&#8221; (1979), symphonic pictures &#8220;Imam Shamil&#8221; (1992), cantatas, overtures, ballads, songs, music for theatrical productions. Grand master of popular and jazz music, he wrote music for 42 films by Russian and foreign film studios. The works of the composer recorded on 33 long-player and 25 compact discs (CD), issued in Russia, Germany, USA and Italy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Murad Kazhlaev &#8211; musician, whom I deeply respect for talent, leaving the roots in the native soil, but who writes beautifully and the orchestra songs of other nations, also in the American and French styles. I send fraternal greetings to him, full of the sympathies&#8221;<br />
         Nino Rota, composer, winner of the International Prize &#8220;Oscar&#8221;, Professor (Italy, 1978.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kim Nazaretov</title>
		<link>/2019/06/kim-nazaretov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 03:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Connections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karachay-Cherkessia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[24.06.1936 &#8211; 18.07.1993 The head of a jazz orchestra, band leader, pianist, arranger, conductor, composer, teacher, Honored Artist of Russia (1985). The first in the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>24.06.1936 &#8211; 18.07.1993</p>
<p>       The head of a jazz orchestra, band leader, pianist, arranger, conductor, composer, teacher, Honored Artist of Russia (1985). The first in the country, Professor of pop and jazz music (1989). One of the founders and creators of pop-jazz education in Russia. The first head of pop and jazz music Rostov College of Art (1982, 1985), the first Head of the Department of pop and jazz music in The Rostov State Conservatoire named after S.V. Rakhmaninov (RGMPI) (1982, 1993). Member, Coordinating Board of Education with a variety of science-based central office to the educational institutions of culture and art (1984, 1993). Founder Rostov Jazz Orchestra (1963, 1993). Winner of the International and local jazz festivals. Chairman of the jury of international and national jazz competitions. By teaching and training manuals for piano and orchestra class for pop-jazz music departments of universities and colleges. The teacher, brought up a lot of winners of international and domestic competitions and festivals, working in Russia, Europe and America. </p>
<p>        &#8220;The elegant, extravagant conductor, Knight of Big Band&#8230; He once perfectly combined intelligence, gentleness and ambitious principles. He understood. But he was so talented person that knew how that their commitment and determination to express in some very good form.&#8221; (YS Saulsky).</p>
<p>        &#8220;His efficiency, combined with humor, combined with his personal charm enabled is very hard to put back on its feet pop-jazz education in Rostov&#8230;&#8221; (VB Feyertag).</p>
<p>       Spring 87th at the initiative of K. Nazaretov in Rostov-na-Don Russia held a contest pop-jazz vocalists, then &#8211; II Donskoj big jazz festival Band, which at this time was already international (attended by teams from Germany, France, Poland). In December 87th as a member of the jury Kim Nazaretov, along with students and graduates og conservatory goes to Poland in the town of Kalisz in the XIV International Jazz Festival and the VII International Competition for jazz pianists named Mstislav Kosza. Already in Kalisz Kim was chosen chairman of the jury at the piano. Rostov musicians I. Ukolov and M. Ivanov were awarded this prestigious competition. In the 88th year, the orchestra was invited on a tour to Scotland in the sister-city Glasgow. In the same year, Kim Avedikovich starts a series of concerts under the rubric of &#8220;Jazz + Jazz&#8221; the Philharmonic. Vladimir Borisovich Feyertag, jazz musician, said: &#8220;Orchestra of Nazaretov pleases us with his persistence, careful attitude namely to jazz instrument&#8221;.</p>
<p>In 1990, Kim Nazareth included in the work of the organization All-Russian competition of jazz musicians and holds it in April (the chairman of jury &#8211; Igor Bril). The winners were essentially two schools: the Moscow and Rostov. In autumn the same year, the chair of pop and jazz music RGMPI joined the International Association of Jazz Schools (Glasgow), which unfolded under the slogan: &#8220;The future of jazz is linked to the future of jazz education and the International Association of Jazz Schools&#8221;. In January 1992,Kim Nazaretov was awarded for the academic title of professor on the faculty of pop and jazz music. In the same year on July 15 the Municipal Music Center was approved, and the Big Band of Kim Nazaretov finally got the status of a professional team. 21 December 1993 municipal Jazz Orchestra of Kim Nazaretova finally and officially moved into its own premises, but &#8230; without Kim.</p>
<p>(from article of Olga Korjova)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Khusyn Gotov</title>
		<link>/2019/06/khusyn-gotov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 02:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Connections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karachay-Cherkessia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Khusyn Azamat-Gerievich Gotov &#8211; Renowned Circassian professional singer-educator and statesman, holds the following titles: Honored Artist of Kabardino-Balkaria Republic, People&#8217;s artist of Karachay-Cherkessia Republic, Honored...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Khusyn Azamat-Gerievich Gotov &#8211; Renowned Circassian professional singer-educator and statesman, holds the following titles: Honored Artist of Kabardino-Balkaria Republic, People&#8217;s artist of Karachay-Cherkessia Republic, Honored Artist of Russian Federation, People&#8217;s Artist of the Russian Federation.<br />
      Khusyn Gotov was born on the 27th of February, 1941 in Jaco village of Karachay-Cherkessian Republic. After graduating from the Saratov State Conservatory in 1972 he continued his professional performance and creative activities as well as his education<br />
      From 1972 to 1974 he was director of the Habez Music School, where he prepared a group of talented young men who won acclaim as they performed across many regions of Russia. During his tenure as director, in 1973, the Habez Music School took part in an international folklore festival called Mountain Land in the Polish People&#8217;s Republic, where Khusyn performed Circassian folk songs.<br />
      From 1974 to 1981 Khusyn Gotov worked as a vocal teacher for the Kamyshin Music School in the Volgograd region, while enjoying a rigorous concert schedule there.<br />
      In 1981, Khusyn Gotov returned to their homeland. From the early days, he started to work as a singing teacher in Cherkessk School Culture and the Arts.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Khusin1.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Khusin1.jpg" alt="" width="454" height="147" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-509" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Khusin1.jpg 454w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Khusin1-300x97.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" /></a></p>
<p>      Khusyn Gotov has been blessed by nature with a wide range and beautiful timbre of voice, and is the first Circassian professional singer. Performing with vivid charm and personality, he has given new life to many songs and poems by local writers and poets. He sings in all of the many languages of the North Caucasus, which is always cause for pride, and promotes a sense of friendship and mutual understanding in his audience. People know and love him, both in Karachay-Cherkessian Republic and far beyond. He is an honorary doctor of Karachay-Cherkessia State University and was awarded the Voice of the Motherland Academy public recognition Kislovodsk Institute of Economics and Law. Since 2003, Khusyn has been the Director of the Karachay-Cherkessia State College of Culture and the Arts. He is a vocal advocate of Soviet-Russian and foreign classics. He continues to make valuable contributions to the development of culture in our country by his activity as a performer, teacher, and as the director of the College of Culture and the Arts. With a great concert of compositions by Russian, Soviet and foreign composers, as well as composers of the North Caucasus, it actively promotes concerts. He has traveled with concerts in Adygea and Abkhazia, Kabardino-Balkaria, has appeared on many concert stages of Russia, Belgium, Holland, Spain, Poland, Turkey and Israel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
