<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>1996 &#8211; Aslan Gotov</title>
	<atom:link href="/aslangotov.github.io/tag/1996/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/aslangotov.github.io/</link>
	<description>Musician, Composer, Arranger</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:14:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/aslangotov.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>1996 &#8211; Aslan Gotov</title>
	<link>/aslangotov.github.io/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>1996. Pop group &#8220;OSHTEN&#8221;</title>
		<link>/aslangotov.github.io/1996/06/1996-pop-group-oshten/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 1996 02:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1996]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/aslangotov.github.io/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The &#8220;Oshten&#8221;, established in 1996, has gradually turned into one of the most popular musical groups, not only in the Republic of Adygea, but also...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The &#8220;Oshten&#8221;, established in 1996, has gradually turned into one of the most popular musical groups, not only in the Republic of Adygea, but also far beyond. The name of the &#8220;Oshten&#8221; from the Circassian language is translated as &#8220;stopped hail&#8221;. Mountain Oshten one of the most beautiful mountains of the Greater Caucasus range.<br />
       The creative team formation is linked with the name of the pianist and composer &#8211; Aslan Gotov. Since 1996, Aslan Gotov is the artistic director and founder of pop group &#8220;Oshten&#8221;. His creative energy, striking composition and performing talent, open the verge of performing ensemble, and to diversify his repertoire: jazz standards, rock and pop music, contemporary songs of Adyghe composers, popular Russian and foreign pop songs. Genre universality of ensemble, possessing a variety of performing styles, professionalism, have become the interpreter of the collective works of many composers of Adygea: U. Thabisimov, D. Natho, A. Nekhay, Yu Chirg, A. Khachak, N. Emizh, M. Hupov, A. Gotov.</p>
<p><a href="/aslangotov.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/oshten01.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/aslangotov.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/oshten01.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-431" /></a></p>
<p>       The brightest feature, the art collective, is rethinking Adyghe folk musical traditions within the framework of traditional jazz styles. Thus, the composer Aslan Gotov prepared block pop-jazz treatments &#8211; &#8220;the pearl&#8221; of Circassian music. In the block represented by the song: &#8220;Scharatym&#8221;, &#8220;Sy Mamat&#8221;, &#8220;Kolen&#8221;, &#8220;Tsyrats&#8221;, &#8220;IstambylyakIo&#8221;, &#8220;Kasey&#8221;, &#8220;Adyif&#8221;, Potpourri on the melodies of Circassian folk dance tunes &#8220;Laparyf-Scheschen&#8221;, &#8220;Kafa kuanche&#8221;, &#8220;Zagatlat&#8221; and &#8220;Islamy&#8221;. On the basis of pop group &#8220;Oshten&#8221; was released CD with recordings of Circassian dance tunes performed by Zalim Irugov (Circassian harmonica), two CD solo album &#8220;Oshten&#8221;, solo album of Ali Khachak . In 1999, in Jordan was issued a joint magnitoalbom of group &#8220;Oshten&#8221; and singer-guitarist Alia Khachak. The records on the radio, participation in television programs, music videos, created a documentary film(directed by Yu. Nekhay) about &#8220;Oshten&#8221;, points to the best concert venues of Adygea and successful tours in the North Caucasus (Kabardino-Balkaria, Karachay-Cherkessia, Stavropol and Krasnodar Krai, Dagestan) &#8211; all this shows the limit saturated creative collective life, and contributes to its growth and strengthen credibility. Popular North-Caucasian singers as: Z. Tutov, T. Nekhay, R. Sheozheva, N. Emizh, M. Guchetl, R. Tletseri, performed with the group &#8220;Oshten&#8221;.<br />
       Numerous festivals and competitions Group &#8220;Oshten&#8221; was awarded: Diploma for active participation and creative contribution to the development of jazz in the VIII and IX of the North Caucasian Jazz (Stavropol 1997-98) Diploma Laureate jazz festival on the 100 years since the birth of George Gershwin (Tuapse, 1998); Laureate Diploma IV interregional festival &#8220;Student Spring&#8221; (Nalchik, 1998); Diploma Laureate Festival (Cherkessk 1999), the diploma of the laureate variety of festival songs, &#8220;Good Neighborhood &#8220;(Elista, 2000); Laureate Diploma IV interregional festival world Caucasus (Makhachkala, 2000).<br />
       The team continues to work and is currently under the leadership of a talented musician and singer Aliy Khachak.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
